http://www.socra.org/privacy-policy/

Conferences & Education
Health and Safety Update (COVID-19)
Privacy Policy
The Society of Clinical Research Professionals (SOCRA) is a 501(c)3 charitable non-profit membership organization whose mission is to provide education, training, and certification for people working in clinical research. SOCRA is committed to maintaining privacy protections for its users. Our Privacy Policy is designed to help you understand how we collect, use and safeguard the information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our service. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. We may change this policy by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are aware of any changes.
Introduction
SOCRA is a membership organization. Our mission is to provide SOCRA members with education and certification to help protect the welfare or research participants and improve global health. Many membership services require the collection of personal data. This data is only used to help provide members with such education and certification services.
SOCRA also understands that everyone has the right to know what personal information organizations hold about them, why and how their information is held and used, with whom their information is shared and for what purpose and for how long their personal information is retained. People also have the right to check that the information held about them is accurate and to object to processing of information that would cause them damage and distress.
Information Provided By Users on the SOCRA Website
SOCRA’s website will prompt you to voluntarily provide personal information if and when it is needed by SOCRA to provide a service or conduct a transaction that you have requested, such as registering for membership, registering for courses and webinars, requesting information, ordering publications, and communicating with SOCRA through email. The types of personal information that you may be asked to provide to SOCRA include your first and last name, home, business or other mailing address, title, company or organization, telephone number, mobile number, fax number, email address, and credit card information.
SOCRA may use your Personal Information to provide services to you upon your request.
Such services may include sending you newsletters and publications, responding to your questions and comments, communicating with you concerning your registration to SOCRA programs, emailing you updates concerning SOCRA membership, products and services, and access to the SOCRA membership directory should you choose not to opt out of the membership directory.
Cookie Policy
How We Use Cookies (Automatically Collected Information on our Website)
A cookie cannot harm your device. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers, which is transferred to your computer hard drive, tablet or mobile device when you visit a website. For further information about cookies, visit www.allaboutcookies.org. However, please note that we are not responsible for the content of any external websites.
The SOCRA website automatically collects certain internet usage information from its visitors. The website uses cookies to monitor individual activity in aggregate to improve the website. Information collected includes the name of your internet service provider and the Internet Protocol (IP) address through which you access the internet, the date and time you access the SOCRA website, the pages that you view while browsing the website, browser types and versions, geographic information, device use, and the internet address of any third-party website from which you linked directly to our website. This information is only used to help improve the SOCRA website, analyze trends and administer the website. All guests to the website can use the open portions anonymously. SOCRA uses analytics data and the DoubleClick cookie to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to our website.
Site visitors may opt out of the DoubleClick cookie by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page or they may opt out of Google Analytics by visiting the Google Analytics opt-out page.
SOCRA does not use or disclose information about your individual visits to www.socra.org, nor do we provide the information you give us on this site to outside companies, without your approval.
Security of Personal Information
SOCRA takes the security of your Personal Information very seriously.
SOCRA takes precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the web site, your information is protected both online and off-line. When your Personal Information is stored by SOCRA, we use reasonable and appropriate measures to protect it from loss, misuse and unauthorized access.
Data transmission over public networks however, cannot be guaranteed to be one hundred percent secure.
While SOCRA will use all reasonable means to protect your Personal Information, SOCRA cannot guarantee the security of your transmissions of such Personal Information, and you use the SOCRA website at your own risk.
Rights to Access and Control Your Personal Data
SOCRA allows members to change your personal data by contacting the SOCRA office.
For personal data that we have about you:
Delete Data: You can ask us to erase or delete all or some of your personal data (e.g., if it is no longer necessary to provide Services to you). If you are certified with SOCRA, we are required to keep your information.
Change or Correct Data: You can edit some of your personal data through your account. You can also ask us to change, update or fix your data in certain cases, particularly if it’s inaccurate.
Object to, or Limit or Restrict, Use of Data: You can ask us to stop using all or some of your personal data (e.g., if we have no legal right to keep using it) or to limit our use of it (e.g., if your personal data is inaccurate or unlawfully held).
Right to Access and/or Take Your Data: You can ask us for a copy of your personal data and can ask for a copy of personal data you provided in machine readable form.
You may also contact us using the contact information below, and we will consider your request in accordance with applicable laws.
Uses by Third-Parties
SOCRA works closely with a certain third party vendors to offer membership and certification services. SOCRA may share member information with these vendors to provide certain SOCRA members with
We do not provide your personally identifiable information to any third party for their own marketing purposes without your prior request or consent.
Opting out of notifications / mailings
SOCRA members may opt out of receiving information from the SOCRA office. Members may request to no longer receive email notifications and/or paper mailings (including the SOCRA quarterly journal).
Other Websites
Please be aware that our Site may contain links to other sites on the Internet that are owned and operated by third parties. The information practices of those websites linked to our website are not covered by this Policy. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of websites to which the website links. If you provide any information to such third parties, different rules regarding the collection and use of your PII may apply. We strongly suggest you review such third party’s privacy policies before providing any data to them.
Contact SOCRA
For any questions, comments, or further information concerning the terms of this Online Privacy Policy, or to request changes to your Personal Information, subject to such limitations as provided herein, please contact SOCRA at 215.882.8644 or office@socra.org
Privacy Policy
The Society of Clinical Research Professionals (SOCRA) is a 501(c)3 charitable non-profit membership organization whose mission is to provide education, training, and certification for people working in clinical research. SOCRA is committed to maintaining privacy protections for its users. Our Privacy Policy is designed to help you understand how we collect, use and safeguard the information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our service. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. We may change this policy by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are aware of any changes.
SOCRA has updated its data protection program to meet the demands of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”). By accessing the SOCRA website you accept our Privacy Policy, and you consent to the collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.
Introduction
SOCRA is a membership organization. Our mission is to provide SOCRA members with education and certification to help protect the welfare or research participants and improve global health. Many membership services require the collection of personal data. This data is only used to help provide members with such education and certification services.
SOCRA also understands that everyone has the right to know what personal information organizations hold about them, why and how their information is held and used, with whom their information is shared and for what purpose and for how long their personal information is retained. People also have the right to check that the information held about them is accurate and to object to processing of information that would cause them damage and distress.
Information Provided By Users on the SOCRA Website
SOCRA’s website will prompt you to voluntarily provide personal information if and when it is needed by SOCRA to provide a service or conduct a transaction that you have requested, such as registering for membership, registering for courses and webinars, requesting information, ordering publications, and communicating with SOCRA through email. The types of personal information that you may be asked to provide to SOCRA include your first and last name, home, business or other mailing address, title, company or organization, telephone number, mobile number, fax number, email address, and credit card information.
SOCRA may use your Personal Information to provide services to you upon your request.  Such services may include sending you newsletters and publications, responding to your questions and comments, communicating with you concerning your registration to SOCRA programs, emailing you updates concerning SOCRA membership, products and services, and access to the SOCRA membership directory should you choose not to opt out of the membership directory.
Cookie Policy
How We Use Cookies (Automatically Collected Information on our Website)
A cookie cannot harm your device. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers, which is transferred to your computer hard drive, tablet or mobile device when you visit a website. For further information about cookies, visit www.allaboutcookies.org. However, please note that we are not responsible for the content of any external websites.
The SOCRA website automatically collects certain internet usage information from its visitors. The website uses cookies to monitor individual activity in aggregate to improve the website. Information collected includes the name of your internet service provider and the Internet Protocol (IP) address through which you access the internet, the date and time you access the SOCRA website, the pages that you view while browsing the website, browser types and versions, geographic information, device use, and the internet address of any third-party website from which you linked directly to our website. This information is only used to help improve the SOCRA website, analyze trends and administer the website. All guests to the website can use the open portions anonymously. SOCRA uses analytics data and the DoubleClick cookie to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to our website.  Site visitors may opt out of the DoubleClick cookie by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page or they may opt out of Google Analytics by visiting the Google Analytics opt-out page.
SOCRA does not use or disclose information about your individual visits to www.socra.org, nor do we provide the information you give us on this site to outside companies, without your approval.
Security of Personal Information
SOCRA takes the security of your Personal Information very seriously.  SOCRA takes precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the web site, your information is protected both online and off-line. When your Personal Information is stored by SOCRA, we use reasonable and appropriate measures to protect it from loss, misuse and unauthorized access.  Data transmission over public networks however, cannot be guaranteed to be one hundred percent secure.  While SOCRA will use all reasonable means to protect your Personal Information, SOCRA cannot guarantee the security of your transmissions of such Personal Information, and you use the SOCRA website at your own risk.
Rights to Access and Control Your Personal Data
SOCRA allows members to change your personal data by contacting the SOCRA office.
For personal data that we have about you:
Delete
Data: You can ask us to erase or
delete all or some of your personal data (e.g., if it is no longer
necessary to provide Services to you). If you are certified with SOCRA, we are required to keep your information.
Change
or Correct Data: You
can edit some of your personal data through your account. You can also ask
us to change, update or fix your data in certain cases, particularly if
it’s inaccurate.
Object
to, or Limit or Restrict, Use of Data: You can ask us to stop using all or some of your personal data (e.g., if
we have no legal right to keep using it) or to limit our use of it (e.g.,
if your personal data is inaccurate or unlawfully held).
Right to
Access and/or Take Your Data: You
can ask us for a copy of your personal data and can ask for a
copy of personal data you provided in machine readable form.
You may also contact us using the contact information below, and we will consider your request in accordance with applicable laws.
Uses by Third-Parties
SOCRA works closely with a certain third party vendors to offer membership and certification services. SOCRA may share member information with these vendors to provide certain SOCRA members with
We do not provide your personally identifiable information to any third party for their own marketing purposes without your prior request or consent.
Opting out of notifications / mailings
SOCRA members may opt out of receiving information from the SOCRA office. Members may request to no longer receive email notifications and/or paper mailings (including the SOCRA quarterly journal).
Other Websites
Please be aware that our Site may contain links to other sites on the Internet that are owned and operated by third parties. The information practices of those websites linked to our website are not covered by this Policy. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of websites to which the website links. If you provide any information to such third parties, different rules regarding the collection and use of your PII may apply. We strongly suggest you review such third party’s privacy policies before providing any data to them.
Contact SOCRA
For any questions, comments, or further information concerning the terms of this Online Privacy Policy, or to request changes to your Personal Information, subject to such limitations as provided herein, please contact SOCRA at 215.882.8644 or office@socra.org
Privacy Policy
The Society of Clinical Research Professionals (SOCRA) is a 501(c)3 charitable non-profit membership organization whose mission is to provide education, training, and certification for people working in clinical research. SOCRA is committed to maintaining privacy protections for its users. Our Privacy Policy is designed to help you understand how we collect, use and safeguard the information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our service. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. We may change this policy by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are aware of any changes.
SOCRA has updated its data protection program to meet the demands of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”). By accessing the SOCRA website you accept our Privacy Policy, and you consent to the collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.
Introduction
SOCRA is a membership organization. Our mission is to provide SOCRA members with education and certification to help protect the welfare or research participants and improve global health. Many membership services require the collection of personal data. This data is only used to help provide members with such education and certification services.
SOCRA also understands that everyone has the right to know what personal information organizations hold about them, why and how their information is held and used, with whom their information is shared and for what purpose and for how long their personal information is retained. People also have the right to check that the information held about them is accurate and to object to processing of information that would cause them damage and distress.
Information Provided By Users on the SOCRA Website
SOCRA’s website will prompt you to voluntarily provide personal information if and when it is needed by SOCRA to provide a service or conduct a transaction that you have requested, such as registering for membership, registering for courses and webinars, requesting information, ordering publications, and communicating with SOCRA through email. The types of personal information that you may be asked to provide to SOCRA include your first and last name, home, business or other mailing address, title, company or organization, telephone number, mobile number, fax number, email address, and credit card information.
SOCRA may use your Personal Information to provide services to you upon your request.
Such services may include sending you newsletters and publications, responding to your questions and comments, communicating with you concerning your registration to SOCRA programs, emailing you updates concerning SOCRA membership, products and services, and access to the SOCRA membership directory should you choose not to opt out of the membership directory.
Cookie Policy
How We Use Cookies (Automatically Collected Information on our Website)
A cookie cannot harm your device. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers, which is transferred to your computer hard drive, tablet or mobile device when you visit a website. For further information about cookies, visit www.allaboutcookies.org. However, please note that we are not responsible for the content of any external websites.
The SOCRA website automatically collects certain internet usage information from its visitors. The website uses cookies to monitor individual activity in aggregate to improve the website. Information collected includes the name of your internet service provider and the Internet Protocol (IP) address through which you access the internet, the date and time you access the SOCRA website, the pages that you view while browsing the website, browser types and versions, geographic information, device use, and the internet address of any third-party website from which you linked directly to our website. This information is only used to help improve the SOCRA website, analyze trends and administer the website. All guests to the website can use the open portions anonymously. SOCRA uses analytics data and the DoubleClick cookie to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to our website.
Site visitors may opt out of the DoubleClick cookie by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page or they may opt out of Google Analytics by visiting the Google Analytics opt-out page.
SOCRA does not use or disclose information about your individual visits to www.socra.org, nor do we provide the information you give us on this site to outside companies, without your approval.
Security of Personal Information
SOCRA takes the security of your Personal Information very seriously.
SOCRA takes precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the web site, your information is protected both online and off-line. When your Personal Information is stored by SOCRA, we use reasonable and appropriate measures to protect it from loss, misuse and unauthorized access.
Data transmission over public networks however, cannot be guaranteed to be one hundred percent secure.
While SOCRA will use all reasonable means to protect your Personal Information, SOCRA cannot guarantee the security of your transmissions of such Personal Information, and you use the SOCRA website at your own risk.
Rights to Access and Control Your Personal Data
SOCRA allows members to change your personal data by contacting the SOCRA office.
For personal data that we have about you:
•	Delete Data: You can ask us to erase or delete all or some of your personal data (e.g., if it is no longer necessary to provide Services to you). If you are certified with SOCRA, we are required to keep your information.
•	Change or Correct Data: You can edit some of your personal data through your account. You can also ask us to change, update or fix your data in certain cases, particularly if it’s inaccurate.
•	Object to, or Limit or Restrict, Use of Data: You can ask us to stop using all or some of your personal data (e.g., if we have no legal right to keep using it) or to limit our use of it (e.g., if your personal data is inaccurate or unlawfully held).
•	Right to Access and/or Take Your Data: You can ask us for a copy of your personal data and can ask for a copy of personal data you provided in machine readable form.
You may also contact us using the contact information below, and we will consider your request in accordance with applicable laws.
Uses by Third-Parties
SOCRA works closely with a certain third party vendors to offer membership and certification services. SOCRA may share member information with these vendors to provide certain SOCRA members with
We do not provide your personally identifiable information to any third party for their own marketing purposes without your prior request or consent.
Opting out of notifications / mailings
SOCRA members may opt out of receiving information from the SOCRA office. Members may request to no longer receive email notifications and/or paper mailings (including the SOCRA quarterly journal).
Other Websites
Please be aware that our Site may contain links to other sites on the Internet that are owned and operated by third parties. The information practices of those websites linked to our website are not covered by this Policy. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of websites to which the website links. If you provide any information to such third parties, different rules regarding the collection and use of your PII may apply. We strongly suggest you review such third party’s privacy policies before providing any data to them.
Contact SOCRA
For any questions, comments, or further information concerning the terms of this Online Privacy Policy, or to request changes to your Personal Information, subject to such limitations as provided herein, please contact SOCRA at 215.882.8644 or office@socra.org
This site uses cookies. You can read how we use them in our privacy policy.
Close
